Guide to the Clive L. DuVal papers, 1960-1994
George Mason University Libraries
- Series 3: Campaign Materials, 1960-1994
  - Questionnaires, 1983 (Box 115, Folder 4)
  - McDiarmid Finance Committee, 1985 (Box 115, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous CLD Campaign, 1983 (Box 115, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous Contributions and Fundraisers (Box 115, Folder 7)
  - CLD Finance Committee, 1983 (Box 115, Folder 8)
  - Invitations (Box 115, Folder 9)
  - Political Addresses (Box 115, Folder 10)
  - Campaign Reports (Box 115, Folder 11)
  - Press Releases, 1983 (Box 118, Folder 1)
  - Page Senate, undated (Box 118, Folder 2)
  - Press Releases prior to 1983, undated (Box 118, Folder 3)
  - Press Releases prior to 1983, undated (Box 118, Folder 4)
  - Voting Results, undated (Box 118, Folder 5)
  - Thank You Letters, undated (Box 118, Folder 6)
  - CLD Literature, undated (Box 118, Folder 7)
  - Baliles for Governor, 1985 (Box 118, Folder 8)
  - Boucher Fundraiser, 1984 (Box 118, Folder 9)
  - Fundraiser - Salona, September 24, 1983 (Box 118, Folder 10)
  - CLD Fundraiser - Salona, September 15, 1983 (Box 118, Folder 11)
  - Literature, Brochures, etc., undated (Box 118, Folder 12)
  - US Senate Race, undated (Box 161, Folder 31)
  - Legislator's Addresses, Phone Numbers and Committee Assignments, undated (Box 161, Folder 32)
  - Gubernatorial Race, 1989 (Box 163, Folder 12)
  - Gubernatorial Race, 1989 (Box 163, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 164, Folder 1)
  - Campaign Reports, 1987 (Box 164, Folder 6)
  - Clive DuVal, Doe, 1991 (Box 164, Folder 7)
  - Howell for Senate, 1991 (Box 164, Folder 8)
  - Press Releases, Vepco Rate Case, undated (Box 164, Folder 12)
  - Polls and Issues, undated (Box 164, Folder 13)
  - Commonwealth of Virginia Senate Legislation, undated (Box 165, Folder 1)
  - Political (1), undated (Box 165, Folder 2)
  - Political (2), undated (Box 165, Folder 3)
  - Speeches, etc., 1970 (Box 165, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 165, Folder 7)
  - Duval's Democratic Daily, undated (Box 165, Folder 8)
  - Campaign Plan - Communications, US Senate Race, 1970 (Box 165, Folder 21)
  - Analysis of the 1966 Campaign for Governor in Pennsylvania, undated (Box 166, Folder 2)
  - Van Landingham for Senator and Other Candidates (2), 1988 (Box 166, Folder 4)
  - Van Landingham for Senator and Other Candidates (1), 1988 (Box 166, Folder 5)
  - Survey of Political Attitudes, undated (Box 166, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 166, Folder 9)
  - Testimony of Alexander F. Skirpan (Box 166, Folder 10)
  - Campaign Plan, 1988 (Box 166, Folder 11)
  - Notes, undated (Box 168, Folder 1)
  - Letters to Newly Registered Voters, undated (Box 169, Folder 1)
  - Fundraiser - Salona, January 10, 1987 (Box 169, Folder 2)
  - Caucus Fundraisers, undated (Box 169, Folder 3)
  - Senate Democratic Caucus, 1990-1991 (Box 169, Folder 4)
  - Senate Democratic Caucus, 1988 (Box 169, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 169, Folder 6)
  - Caucus Joint Fundraiser, March 8, 1991 (Box 169, Folder 7)
  - Staff Campaign, 1987 (Box 169, Folder 8)
  - Financial Disclosure Forms (Box 169, Folder 9)
  - Northern Virginia Delegation, 1989 (Box 169, Folder 10)
  - Senate Democratic Caucus, 1987 (Box 169, Folder 11)
  - Northern Virginia Delegation, 1990 (Box 169, Folder 12)
  - Delegate Candidates, 1989 (Box 171, Folder 5)
  - Senate Campaign, 1994 (Box 171, Folder 6)
  - Senate Caucus, 1989 (Box 171, Folder 7)
  - Political, undated (Box 171, Folder 8)
  - League of Women Voters of the Fairfax Area, undated (Box 172, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous Campaign, undated (Box 172, Folder 11)
  - Sketch of the Laws, Passed at the Legislature in 1832-1833, Framed, undated (Box 172, Folder 11)
- Series 4: McLean Citizens Association, 1960-1962
  This series documents DuVal's work as president of the McLean Citizens Association (MCA). The records portray efforts to reverse a rezoning decision made by the Fairfax County Board of Supervisors as requested by developer Sheldon Magazine. Magazine sought the rezoning for the purpose of constructing apartment units in an area known as Merrywood located on Route 123. Development of this tract of land was viewed by the MCA and others as a threat to the environment of the Potomac Gorge located above the Key Bridge between Virginia and the District of Columbia. The matter went before a Grand Jury in 1962 which examined the potential involvement of County officials in criminal activity regarding the rezoning application. Records include correspondence, meeting minutes, resolutions, records of public hearings, petitions in opposition to rezoning, legal research, legal documents, press releases, news clippings, photographs, and slides.
  - Bros - Ridder, 1960 (Box 77, Folder 1)
  - Generalized Zoning Map, 1960 (Box 77, Folder 2)
  - Notes Re: Sheldon Magazine Application for Rezoning, 1960 (Box 77, Folder 3)
  - Rezoning Application, Appeal, 1960 (Box 77, Folder 4)
  - Grand Jury, 1960 (Box 77, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, Sheldon Magazine Application for Rezoning, 1960 (Box 77, Folder 6)
  - Sheldon Magazine Application for Rezoning, 1960 (Box 77, Folder 7)
  - Bill to Help Preserve the Potomac River, 1960 (Box 77, Folder 8)
  - Citizen Support, 1960 (Box 77, Folder 9)
  - Constitutionality of Congressional Authority to Regulate Zoning, 1962 (Box 77, Folder 10)
  - Slides, 1960 (Box 77, Folder 11)
  - Petition in Opposition to Magazine Application, 1960 (Box 77, Folder 12)
  - Magazine Application for Rezoning; Publicity Material, 1960 (Box 77, Folder 13)
  - Haycock Road Improvements Project, McLean Virginia Fairfax County, undated (Box 151, Folder 2)
  - Haycock Road Improvements Project, McLean Virginia Fairfax County, undated (Box 151, Folder 3)
  - Haycock Road Improvements Project, McLean Virginia Fairfax County, undated (Box 151, Folder 4)
  - Haycock Road Improvements Project, McLean Virginia Fairfax County, undated (Box 151, Folder 5)
  - Haycock Road Improvements Project, McLean Virginia Fairfax County, undated (Box 152, Folder 1)
  - Haycock Road Improvements Project, McLean Virginia Fairfax County, undated (Box 152, Folder 2)
- Series 5: Virginians for Dulles, 1968-1981
  This series documents DuVal's work as president of Virginians for Dulles (VFD), a citizen action group that sought to reduce aircraft noise and emmissions by rerouting air traffic from Washington National to Dulles International Airport. The series includes meeting minutes, correspondence between VFD board members, financial records, telephone messages, and by-laws for Virginians for Dulles and other groups seeking to mitigate airport nuisance. Also included are legal briefs of suits filed by VFD against Washington National Airport and transcripts of testimony before the Aviation Subcommittee of the US House Committee on Public Works and Transportation. For additional materials on Virginians for Dulles see the finding aid for the.
  - Virginians for Dulles, 1968-1969 (Box 78, Folder 1)
  - Virginians for Dulles, 1970 (Box 78, Folder 2)
  - Virginians for Dulles, 1971 (Box 78, Folder 3)
  - Virginians for Dulles, 1972 (Box 78, Folder 4)
  - Virginians for Dulles, 1973 (Box 78, Folder 5)
  - Virginians for Dulles, 1974 (Box 78, Folder 6)
  - Virginians for Dulles, 1975 (Box 78, Folder 7)
  - Virginians for Dulles, 1980 [A] (Box 79, Folder 1)
  - Virginians for Dulles, 1980 [B] (Box 79, Folder 2)
  - Virginians for Dulles, 1980 [C] (Box 79, Folder 3)
  - Virginians for Dulles, 1980 [D] (Box 79, Folder 4)
  - Virginians for Dulles, 1980 [E] (Box 79, Folder 5)
  - Virginians for Dulles - Contributions, undated (Box 80, Folder 1)
  - Virginians for Dulles, 1981 [A] (Box 80, Folder 2)
  - Virginians for Dulles, 1981 [B] (Box 80, Folder 3)
  - Virginians for Dulles, 1981 [C] (Box 80, Folder 4)
- Series 6: Press Releases and Constituent Newsletters, 1966-1987
  This series contains official press releases on legislative and campaign topics. The newsletters include published reports on legislation in progress, activities of the General Assembly, and anecdotes about the legislation session. From 1966-1987 the newsletter was titled "DuVal's Democratic Daily, and in 1988 its title was changed to "The DuVal Dispatch."
  - Press Releases, 1967-1968 (Box 81, Folder 1)
  - Press Releases, 1969 (Box 81, Folder 2)
  - Press Releases, 1970-1974 (Box 81, Folder 3)
  - Press Releases, 1975-1979 (Box 81, Folder 4)
  - DuVal Daily [Newsletters], 1966-1987 (Box 81, Folder 5)
  - DuVal Dispatch [Newsletters], undated (Box 81, Folder 6)
  - Newsletters, 1977 (Box 81, Folder 7)
  - Newsletters, 1988 (Box 92, Folder 17)
  - Press Releases, undated (Box 93, Folder 9)
  - Newsletter Articles, undated (Box 113, Folder 5)
  - DuVal's Daily, June 18, 1965 - March 6, 1987 (Box 156, Folder 1)
  - Newsletters Other Than Clive DuVal's, 1975 (Box 161, Folder 2)
- Series 7: Printed Materials, 1963-1989
  This series contains various published journals dealing with the environment, constitutional reform in Virginia, or nuclear regulation.
  - Printed Materials (Box 81, Folder 8)
    - Virginia's Common Wealth: A Program for Citizen Action, undated; 1.
      3 copies
    - Virginia's Common Wealth: A Study of Virginia's Outdoor Recreation Resources and the... Plan for Conserving and Developing Them, undated; 2.
    - Annual Report - Virginia Electric and Power Company, 1973; 3.
    - Model State Constitution, Sixth Edition (Revised), 1963; 4.
    - Howard, Dick A. E. et a. - State Constitutional Revision, 1968; 5.
    - Subcommittee on Oversight and Investigations, Committee on the Interstate and Foreign Commerce, House of Representatives Ninety-Fourth Congress, Second Session, November 4, 1976; 6.
    - Subcommittee on Reports, Accounting, and Management, Committee on Government Operations; United States Senate Ninety-Fourth Congress, First Session, July 22, 24, 1975; 7.
    - William and Mary Law Review, Vol. 10 No. 2, 1968; 8.
  - Northern Virginia Facts and Figures, undated (Box 150, Folder 3)
  - Virginia Facts and Figures, 1985 (Box 153, Folder 17)
  - Metropolitan Washington Regional Directory, 1986 (Box 153, Folder 18)
  - Commonwealth of Virginia State Board of Elections, undated (Box 153, Folder 19)
  - Northern Virginia Transportation Commission Handbook, 1989 (Box 153, Folder 20)
  - Legislative Vote History Digest, undated (Box 167, Folder 1)
  - Commonwealth of Virginia Telephone Directory, August 15, 1978 (Box 170, Folder 9)
  - Commonwealth of Virginia Telephone Directory, August 15, 1978 (Box 171, Folder 9)